<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Firebase on Leif&#39;s Development Blog-o-rama</title>
    <link>https://leifwells.github.io/tags/firebase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Firebase on Leif&#39;s Development Blog-o-rama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; Leif Wells, leifwells.github.io and leifwells.com, 2016. Unauthorized use and/or duplication of this material without express and written permission from this site’s author and/or owner is strictly prohibited. Excerpts and links may be used, provided that full and clear credit is given to Leif Wells, leifwells.github.io and leifwells.com with appropriate and specific direction to the original content.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 12:21:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leifwells.github.io/tags/firebase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularFire 2 at the AngularJS Mountain View Meetup</title>
      <link>https://leifwells.github.io/2016/04/16/angularfire-2-at-the-angularjs-mountain-view-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 12:21:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leifwells.github.io/2016/04/16/angularfire-2-at-the-angularjs-mountain-view-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m building an Ionic 2 starter with social login using Firebase!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; said hundreds of developers participating in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic/blob/2.0/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;Ionic 2 beta&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m doing it as well. It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad idea. Usually, if your app uses online data your users will be required to login. Creating a starter app &amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; a set of code from which you can base a new application upon &amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; would certainly save time and effort creating new applications. In this case it will also give you a good feel for the new way of doing things in Ionic 2. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firebase.com/&#34;&gt;Firebase&lt;/a&gt; is a great service that allows you to easily create social logins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to create my social login starter for weeks. There are several Firebase-related &lt;a href=&#34;http://angular.io&#34;&gt;Angular 2&lt;/a&gt; example apps available on github that were created using &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularfire2.com&#34;&gt;AngularFire 2&lt;/a&gt; or just using the Firebase TypeScript definitions, but I could only get one of them to actually work. One problem has been that AngularFire, the project that everyone uses with Firebase in their Angular 1 projects, simply hasn&amp;rsquo;t been ready for use with Angular 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find a link to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/AngularJS-MTV/events/229520562/&#34;&gt;AngularJS Mountain View Meetup March meeting&lt;/a&gt; video which has several really great presentations. The feature presentation is AngularFire in Angular 2 by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jeffbcross&#34;&gt;Jeff Cross&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_davideast&#34;&gt;David East&lt;/a&gt;. While riddled with sarcasm, the presentation is also riddled with great information on how to use AngularFire 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the code samples from this presentation, I was able to create a authentication service in Ionic 2 that uses Google, Twitter and github social login. I&amp;rsquo;ll post information about that project in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AngularFire 2 is still in development and I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it for anything beyond social login so far. As always, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/EverythingIsInBeta?src=hash&#34;&gt;#EverythingIsInBeta&lt;/a&gt; so your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AngularFire 2 presentation starts the 28 minute mark, but don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to watch the entire set of presentations. I found the &amp;ldquo;How to create an Angular 2 app from scratch&amp;rdquo; presentation very valuable.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/ngnSOTSS8Q8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>