<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Leif&#39;s Development Blog-o-rama</title>
    <link>http://leifwells.com/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Leif&#39;s Development Blog-o-rama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; Leif Wells, leifwells.github.io and leifwells.com, 2016. Unauthorized use and/or duplication of this material without express and written permission from this site’s author and/or owner is strictly prohibited. Excerpts and links may be used, provided that full and clear credit is given to Leif Wells, leifwells.github.io and leifwells.com with appropriate and specific direction to the original content.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 14:57:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://leifwells.com/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned: Unnamed Project 2016-05</title>
      <link>http://leifwells.com/2016/05/28/lessons-learned-unnamed-project-2016-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 14:57:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leifwells.com/2016/05/28/lessons-learned-unnamed-project-2016-05/</guid>
      <description>An Unnamed Project Last month my friends at Skyward Interactive requested my assistance with a project that needed a cross-platform mobile solution. The project, which will remain unnamed because the client is a start-up, is a prototype for a service and required phone, tablet and server development. The phone apps is for customers, the tablet app is for administrators and the server ties them all together.
For mobile development Skyward typically builds native iOS applications, but most of their iOS resources were tied up with other projects and since this project had a short deadline and budget they asked me if I could assemble the iOS and Android phone solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>